

SACHIDA NAND SINGH

Klp Type 3 / 20 , Airforce hindan , Ghaziabad , 201004 7073381379 | SachidanandSingh38@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sachida-nand-singh-719b91225

OBJECTIVE

I am a veteran, an alumnus Indian Air Force can pursue a Challenging Career and be a part of a progressive organization that gives a scope to enhance my knowledge and utilize my skills towards the growth of the organization.

EXPERIENCE

INDIAN AIR FORCE

(June 2001 - June 2022)

Ex. Junior Warrant Officer

Planning and execution of training program, Preparation of syllabus and training material as well as an instructor imparting practical and theoretical training.

- 1. General administration, Office Management, and Co-ordination of operational activities.
- 2. Team lead and supervisor for electronics and communication systems eg.

Dornier 228 201 aircraft 1st and 2nd line servicing MATCAL (Mobile Air Transportable Calibration Lab) Calibration and repair of GPTE as well as STTE etc Mobile communication Terminal (BEL), Air Combat simulator,

(Oct 2003 to Oct 2008) (Oct 2008 to Aug 2014)

(Aug 2014 to Sep 2017) (Sep 2017 to Present)

- 3. Store and Inventory Management as Inventory Holder, Liaisons with Logistics section (2014 to 2022)
- 4. Aviation safety, office safety information security and other security related duties. (2003 to 2022)
- 5. Trained and mentored employees to maximize the team performance.

(2014 to 2022)

6. Guided teams in product merchandising and Inventory management.

(2014 to 2022)

EDUCATION

- NIMS University , Jaipur 2016-2018
 Master Of Business Administration (HR) 60.30%
- JGNOU,New Delhi 2012

Diploma of Higher Education (Electronics)

IGNOU ,New Delhi

2012

Certificate of Higher Education (Security Management of Strategic Installation)

 Patna University , Patna, BR 2008

Bachelor of Arts (Sociology)

DGCA BAMEC Paper I & II Cleared

SKILLS

Security, Administration and Management

•

Team and Vender Management
Interpersonal skills. Simulator Ground
Instructor

Microsoft Office, Facility Management

STRENGTH

- · A good team player.
- · Ability to adapt to diverse culture.
- · Can take any responsibility and give long
- hours. Conversant with computers.
- Analytical approach.
- Quick learner of new technologies

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

Managing computers and laptops for office automation purposes including MS word, PowerPoint,
 Effective surfing for research purpose and data collection.

Worked in computers for e MMS (Maintenance Management System),

IMMOLS (Integrated Materials Management online System),

Automatic Calibration and

Maintained Aircraft form e-700.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Technical Lead skilled in business, (Six sigma and kaizen concept)
 Military Aviation, Engineering and flight Simulation. Strong Engineering professional with a Master Of Business Administration-MBA focused in Human Resources Management/Personal Administration.

21 years of experience in Indian Air Force, Worked as tech Adjutant in Air Combat Simulator and head member of tech team, with a flexible nature of learning any new technology and ready to take any challenging work. Having experience of Inventory handling, Calibration and repair of electronics equipment, Worked in heavy Aircraft (Dornier), Worked in Aircraft Simulator, Worked in Mobile Communication Terminal (Satellite Communication).

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 15/01/1983Marital Status : MarriedNationality : Indian

Permanent Address

Kalawati Kunj

High school road kurthaul

Patna Bihar, Pin 804453